Nathaniel Ehrlich

<u>nwehrlich@gmail.com</u> | 720.697.9293 | Denver, CO 80220 <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nwehrlich</u> | <u>https://github.com/TechnoPrep</u> | <u>https://www.nwehrlich.com/</u>

Summary

Web Developer with a background in Customer Service. Constant self-reflection to see what there is to learn from a situation, and how this can help the development of the best version of myself. Recognized as proactive, resourceful, and persistent problem-solver. Excellent communicator with effective client relationship-building skills. Graduate of Web Development Bootcamp through the University Of Denver.

Technical Skills

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, ReactJS, PHP, Bootstrap, AJAX, Bulma, FontAwesome, Handlebars MVC, Ruby, Rails.

Backend: GraphQL, MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB, Express, Node.JS, REST API, Java JDK 11, IIS. Cloud Services: AzureDev Ops, Azure Data Factory, Azure Blob Storage, AzureAD, Azure App Insight.

Projects

Total Ticket | http://total-ticket.com/ Express / Node Expert | Dataflow Doctor | API Researcher | Database Administrator

- Event Ticket Price Comparison app
- This application creates a centralized platform to connect event-goers to their favorite performers and venues, allowing them to find the best ticket, for the best price across multiple Ticket Purchasing sites.
- JavaScript, GraphQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Heroku, JSON Web Token, Apollo, React, Session Management

Remindr | https://github.com/LoopySquare/Remindr | https://remindr-notification.herokuapp.com/ Project Manager | Express / Node Expert | Database Administrator

- Email / SMS (In Development) notification app
- This application allows you to set notification reminders from the Dashboard for follow-up emails. Roled involved Lead Developer of the Project, delegating responsibilities to other members and holding Stand-Ups to resolve blockers. Created the API management between front-end and back-end Database communication.
- JavaScript, JQuery, Sequelize, NodeJS, Heroku, JawsDB MySQL, Session Management

Relevant Work Experience

Junior Achievement

Apr. 2021 – Current

Application Administrator

Denver, CO

- Handle 8 different applications, managing their Databases and App Services in Azure.
- Actively monitor Apps using Application Insights in Azure for potential issues or bottlenecks.
- Manage 4 applications in Development Stage with 3rd Party Developers in an Agile environment.
- Migrated 4 applications in Development from 3rd party Devs repositories to our Azure DevOps and TFS.
- Setting up CI/CD Pipelines for new Projects in Azure DevOps.

- Setup, configure and troubleshoot WebApps built-in IIS on local user networks.
- Responsible for resolving end-user application issues across 103 Junior Achievement Areas.
- Created internal documentation for the Infrastructure Team to resolve Database Issues.
- Managing bug triaging and proposing solutions to our 3rd Party Development Teams.
- Manage Hybrid Active Directory environment with On-Prem and AzureAD.
- Create custom reports from SQL Databases for heads of Departments.

SchoolMessenger

Jun. 2016 - Apr. 2021

Customer Solution Expert

Joplin, MO

- Developed custom PHP scripts for user data from multiple Student Information Systems (SIS) to our application
- Developed custom SQL queries to extract data from multiple SISs using PHP and ODBC connections.
- Wrote custom Shell scripts on Linux SFTP server to handle user data stored on our SFTP server.
- Developed documentation for SIS integration, and Custom Mobile App deployment processes
- Liaison between the Support and Development Team, Reporting Outages and working with internal teams to notify customers of issues and to ensure they were resolved in a timely fashion.
- Responsible for the largest School District in Canada that serves 247,000 students yearly as the primary contact, developing custom PHP scripts and database queries.
- Managed publishing custom mobile apps to both Android and Apple App Store.
- Managed migration of custom mobile apps from Google Analytics to Firebase / Blg Query Analytics.
- Supported +100 CMS Websites with custom CSS, HTML, and Javascript.

Additional Work Experience

EGS Solutions

Customer Care Specialist

Joplin, MO

- Maintained highest consistent CSAT score for 2 consecutive years.
- Assisted end-users with Intuit Tax Software, Desktop, and Online Application.
- Lead training classes with other facilitators during peak season.
- Worked directly with Intuit Management to help resolve bottlenecks during peak season.

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: University of Denver, Denver, CO Dec 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript,

JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Java Programming Masterclass: Udemy

Apr 2022

An 80-hour course on the fundamentals of Java development in JDK 11 and Object-Oriented Programming as Preparation for the Oracle JDK 11 certification course.

AlgoExpert: AlgoExpert.io

Apr 2022 - Current

A website built to help prepare users for technical interviews and algorithms involving in-depth training on Data structures and Big-O notation, System Administration, and FrontEnd Development.

Learn to Code with Ruby & Complete Ruby on Rails Developer Course: Udemy May 2022 A complete guide to Ruby on Rails course on creating applications with the MVC Framework.